<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Building U</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.building-u.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.building-u.com</link>
	<description>A place for postsecondary plans</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 13:29:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://www.building-u.com/wp-content/uploads/BUlogoA-150x150.png</url>
	<title>Building U</title>
	<link>https://www.building-u.com</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>BLOCKCHAIN IN REAL LIFE&#8230;for regular people</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/blockchain-in-real-life-for-regular-people/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/blockchain-in-real-life-for-regular-people/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 18:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.building-u.com/?p=4692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What are you passionate about? Don’t worry, we’re not about to ask you what you want to be when you grow up. What activity makes you feel excited, at ease, or truly yourself? Chances are, the way you do what you love is going to be revolutionized by blockchain technology, and probably sooner than you [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are you passionate about? Don’t worry, we’re not about to ask you what you want to be when you grow up. What activity makes you feel excited, at ease, or truly yourself? Chances are, the way you do what you love is going to be revolutionized by blockchain technology, and probably sooner than you think.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we hear the word ‘blockchain’, we usually think of an inaccessible and confusing world of tech terms that we can’t relate to. Unfortunately, the general population isn’t given much information about blockchain beyond the world of coin-trading.  What we don’t often hear is how blockchain technology will be making new things possible for artists, gamers, doctors, musicians, athletes, social activists… you name it. So, how does this all happen? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, blockchain is really just a sequential chain of information that is unchangeable and has been verified. In simpler terms, it’s a secure ledger. This may seem more than a bit strange: ledgers have been around forever. How would something so antiquated and already known change my life? Well it’s a ledger with a twist &#8212; It’s a ledger that can allow for accurate and secure input and recording of information (around money or whatever is involved in the transaction) between parties who don’t even know each other, located anywhere;  and this can happen directly with no third party intermediary &#8212; like your bank, or Ebay, or Paypal, or… &#8212; meaning no fee-grabbing or potential for personal-information-hijacking! It’s based on peer-to-peer transactions &#8212; meaning securely recording whatever is supposed to have happened between the parties in the transaction directly without some central authority… so it is “decentralized”. Although this secure decentralized ledger can be (and already has been) used with other things besides money, the most well-known application of blockchain is cryptocurrency. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cryptocurrency (meaning the 1000’s of coins/tokens on exchanges, not just Bitcoin) is just one particular application of blockchain, just as email is one particular application of the internet. And just as it is true, but limiting, to suggest that the Internet is simply the place to use and access email, it is true but limiting to suggest that blockchain is simply about Cryptocurrency. Let’s bring to light some of those other things that blockchain ledgers can be used for.</span></p>
<p><b>Art and Music:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Artists today are able to share their work to huge audiences online, which is great for their exposure. But, exposure doesn’t pay rent. Nowadays, lots of artists aren’t getting compensated fairly for their work, partly because of how rampant online art and music theft is. But, what if each piece you uploaded was guaranteed to always be credited, and couldn’t be resold without your permission? What if you didn’t have to rely on any ‘middle-man’ platforms to earn money for your work, and could be paid fully as the creator? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where blockchain comes in. You could upload a digital drawing, song, video, tweet, or even a meme to the blockchain, and from that point on, you will be compensated fairly for however it is used. The system, though, isn’t perfect, and there have been incidents of scammers uploading other peoples’ works to the blockchain</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">1</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to claim the profits for themselves. Additionally, the most popular blockchain platforms used right now have the information about transactions (blocks) validated  by a process that requires lots of energy consumption and are thus not very eco-friendly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">2</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. But, once theft-detection becomes more efficient, and the more eco-friendly validation processes that have been developed are adopted by more blockchain technologies</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">3</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, artists and creators could be empowered in a way we’ve never seen before. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Think of how independent musicians could benefit from being compensated directly by their listeners, fully for their work, without music platforms and labels taking off a percentage from every dollar earned</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">4</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Even as the consumer, there are benefits. Concert-ticket scalping could be eliminated by inputting ticket data as a designated purchase price, determined by and paid to the creator&#8230;making live music more affordable and accessible to fans (who can get tickets before they are gone!)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">5</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><b>Social Media:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Digital media of the 21st century has redefined how we communicate. The images, sounds, and abbreviated text of social media shape our perspectives and how we interact with the world. It’s regarded as a necessary tool both for business and personal interaction; though certainly in its current application, social media can be addictive, and often feeds us information that only confirms our pre-existing beliefs. Blockchain could break these information-bubbles and encourage more productive discourse online.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Steemit is a social media platform that uses blockchain both to validate posts and comments and reward contributors for input.  The platform has been around since 2016 and rewards users with cryptocurrency (Steem Dollars), which can be easily traded for Bitcoin or another exchange traded cryptocurrency and then converted to a “fiat” (national) currency of choice</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">6</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “Many traditional social media companies have made lots of money through the content produced by their users. However, what sets Steem apart is the support it offers to its users by rewarding them for their valuable input to the platform.”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">7</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Its main premise is to serve the community and ensure that those who provide value are rewarded. The implications of rewarding value in content, comment, or validation in social media go beyond individual payment. We are living in polarizing times, and the internet isn’t often the best platform to engage in productive discussions, as it doesn’t always reward nuance, and can become bogged-down in hateful speech. The idea of rewarding valuable content from varying perspectives could enhance our democracy by encouraging productive discourse between opposing viewpoints.</span></p>
<p><b>Control of Personal Data:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain also provides the opportunity for you to take control of your own data. Incidents like the twitter hack in July 2020 where the twitter accounts of various highly prominent and influential people ( Bill Gates, Elon Musk and Joe Biden among others)</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">8</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and the infamous LinkedIn data dump in 2016 which exposed email/password combinations of approximately 117 million people all highlight the importance of data privacy</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">9</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Blockchain could help address a range of  problems associated with data privacy. For starters, the ledger system would mean that there would be no central company or sole authority controlling or selling your data and making decisions based on their interests. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain could also help revolutionize digital identities by aiding in keeping data secure with the aid of “</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">identification systems [that]  are secure, irrefutable, unique and pretty much impossible for an outside source to gain access to without the proper authorization”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">10</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Blockchain could help do things such as aid homeless citizens by securely identifying them without a physical copy of an ID which can be lost, tampered with or stolen</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">11</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furthermore, it could also help refugees. According to the head of the U.N Women’s humanitarian unit, Caroline Rusten,” </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">blockchain could be used to create a secure, paperless record of skills and education that refugees can carry with them, to which information can be added as they are on the move, [allowing] people to be appreciated for who they are and the qualifications they have and not just (be) seen as refugees”</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">12</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain could also encourage greater participation in voting as it has the potential to create voting systems that preserve anonymity, while also allowing for auditing to prevent record tampering. This would essentially mean that people would potentially be able to vote from their phones securely, eliminating (or significantly reducing) obstacles around their vote remaining anonymous that could have previously deterred eligible voters from participating</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">13</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>Sports:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve all heard of incidents in which an athlete was caught doping, or in which an athlete was falsely accused of it. Just earlier in 2021, Shelby Houlihan’s testing positive for nandrolone gave rise to extremely controversial discussions on social media, with many disagreeing with her Olympics ban</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">14</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Blockchain is one way to make medical records that have to do with these tests in the sports industry more accessible and transparent</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">15</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Because of its unchangeable and transparent nature, blockchain is the ideal solution for verifying certain information as well as making appropriate and relevant information publicly available. This would increase the reliability of player stats and testing records</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">16</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, with information being accurate and accessible for the general public or for appropriate parties, using either private or public blockchains. This applies to the entire healthcare industry, where current methods of recording and sharing patient information are unreliable and insecure. By using private blockchains, medical records could be shared between multiple practitioners to verify the information, which could greatly reduce misdiagnosis and medical malpractice.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">17</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><b>Climate Change:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve been talking about how one of blockchain’s biggest strengths is that it ‘decentralizes’ systems. Climate change is yet another subject in which this strength of blockchain comes into play. Blockchain can create decentralized markets for clean energy… meaning a market in which a store of energy can be traded with neighbors, empowering people to produce and store their own renewable energy</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">18</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Blockchain is essentially the only way to enable energy trading among people, and therefore a great way to incentivize renewable energy options among individuals in a community. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beyond individuals and the community, because of its transparency, blockchain can make for accurate, transparent tracking in the reporting of carbon emissions and for accounting for any corporate initiatives contributing to reducing them. This could come into play with the Paris Agreement, for example, which requires this kind of verification and transparency. Countries and organizations would be held responsible for inputting accurate information about their actions to limit/reverse climate change&#8211;meaning two countries wouldn’t be able to take the responsibility for one action</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">19</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Blockchain is an inherently clear, chronologically validated record of all initiatives completed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The above are just a few examples within a few industries where it’s easy to see how  blockchain can be applied and the difference it can make. Many blockchains are set up to DO something &#8212; address an issue of some sort. But there are ones that are set up to essentially &#8216;do nothing&#8217;, too. Either way, all blockchains are ‘powered by’ tokens (crypto-coins).  Tokens are valued, and can be viewed, a bit like traditional stocks in that they can be bought and sold and traded. And, again like traditional stock, their value is determined by the number of people who buy and sell them at any given time. </span></p>
<p><b>Just a bit about Cryptocurrency:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given this, the cryptocurrency associated with any particular blockchain can be used as a new tool to grow your own financial investments. You can purchase coins associated with specific blockchains to invest in your belief in their technologies powering the future (or present), or you could simply purchase them as an investment in your belief about the popularity of the tokens themselves. It&#8217;s a bit like the stock market: similar to making investments based on how well you think a business will perform, you can invest in how well you think a technology will perform/be adopted… OR similar to investing in popular stocks that seem to be holding value over time, you can invest in crypto-coins based on their performance over time as well</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">20</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although investing in cryptocurrency may be generally regarded as a riskier form of investing, it is most definitely already disrupting the world of investing and financial tech</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">21</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Learning about it and your options in it doesn’t have to be threatening or scary. Organizations like CryptoChicks</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">22</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> provide free and extremely low cost educational resources and programs to teach blockchain tech skills and financial literacy to people, especially focusing on women and youth &#8212; those who are currently underrepresented in the tech world. Their goal is to help people to take advantage of the potential of blockchain and how it can build wealth and careers. </span></p>
<p><b>In the End:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, with all of these incredible applications, why aren’t we being taught about blockchain in school? Why can I sign up for a crash course on coding, but not on blockchain development? There is no clear answer to these questions, just as there’s no clear answer as to why all high school students aren’t being taught how to do their taxes. Unfortunately, blockchain technology has been pigeon-holed by many educators as just a means to trade Cryptocoins, which doesn’t seem as relevant to students’ futures. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It might be up to us as students to demand our educators to teach us the relevant skills that could define our future careers. In a way, we’re in a similar place to where the last generations were when the Internet was first invented, and as we know now, if you weren’t able to adapt to the world wide web, you were left in the dust&#8230; Hopefully, the more students and more that they learn about blockchain, the more we can push for better access to workshops and curriculums that will foster our success when we adapt to this new tech. Not only for the sake of our future careers, but also so that we can all have a voice when the world decides what a future running on blockchain will look like. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Footnotes:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">1 </span><a href="https://www.coindesk.com/stop-tokenizing-art-you-dont-own"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.coindesk.com/stop-tokenizing-art-you-dont-own</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> ; </span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/20/22334527/nft-scams-artists-opensea-rarible-marble-cards-fraud-art"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/20/22334527/nft-scams-artists-opensea-rarible-marble-cards-fraud-art</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2 </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/15/22328203/nft-cryptoart-ethereum-blockchain-climate-change</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">3 </span><a href="https://branch.climateaction.tech/issues/issue-2/a-guide-to-ecofriendly-cryptoart-nfts/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://branch.climateaction.tech/issues/issue-2/a-guide-to-ecofriendly-cryptoart-nfts/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">4 </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lAMLYP0Nx2A&amp;feature=emb_imp_woyt"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lAMLYP0Nx2A&amp;feature=emb_imp_woyt</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">5 </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><a href="https://www.bam.fan/nft-ticketing-on-blockchain/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.bam.fan/nft-ticketing-on-blockchain/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">6 </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><a href="https://steem.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://steem.com/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">7 </span><a href="https://buycryptocurrencies.ca/steem#:~:text=Many%20traditional%20social%20media%20companies,valuable%20input%20to%20the%20platform"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://buycryptocurrencies.ca/steem#:~:text=Many%20traditional%20social%20media%20companies,valuable%20input%20to%20the%20platform</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">8 </span><a href="https://www.dfs.ny.gov/Twitter_Report#:~:text=On%20July%2015%2C%202020%2C%20a,assigned%20to%20high%2Dprofile%20users"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.dfs.ny.gov/Twitter_Report#:~:text=On%20July%2015%2C%202020%2C%20a,assigned%20to%20high%2Dprofile%20users</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">9 </span><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/06/how-linkedins-password-sloppiness-hurts-us-all/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/06/how-linkedins-password-sloppiness-hurts-us-all/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">10  </span><a href="https://www.1kosmos.com/blockchain/why-is-blockchain-important/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.1kosmos.com/blockchain/why-is-blockchain-important/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">11  </span><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6425314/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6425314/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">12 </span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-un-refugees-blockchain-idUSKBN19C0BB"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.reuters.com/article/us-un-refugees-blockchain-idUSKBN19C0BB</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">13  </span><a href="https://digitalchamber.org/the-future-of-voting-is-blockchain/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://digitalchamber.org/the-future-of-voting-is-blockchain/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">14  </span><a href="https://www.self.com/story/shelby-houlihan-nandrolone-burrito"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.self.com/story/shelby-houlihan-nandrolone-burrito</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">15 </span><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/337285469_Blockchain_Technology_for_Trustworthy_Doping_Control_Data_Management"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.researchgate.net/publication/337285469_Blockchain_Technology_for_Trustworthy_Doping_Control_Data_Management</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">16 </span><a href="https://academy.ivanontech.com/blog/blockchain-use-cases-in-the-sports-and-esports-industry"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://academy.ivanontech.com/blog/blockchain-use-cases-in-the-sports-and-esports-industry</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">17  </span><a href="https://www.news-medical.net/health/Blockchain-Applications-in-Healthcare.aspx"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.news-medical.net/health/Blockchain-Applications-in-Healthcare.aspx</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">18 </span><a href="https://academic.oup.com/ce/article/5/1/104/6166927"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://academic.oup.com/ce/article/5/1/104/6166927</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">19  </span><a href="https://unfccc.int/blog/the-good-the-bad-and-the-blockchain"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://unfccc.int/blog/the-good-the-bad-and-the-blockchain</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">20 </span><a href="https://vocal.media/theChain/10-major-differences-between-crypto-and-stocks"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://vocal.media/theChain/10-major-differences-between-crypto-and-stocks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">21 </span><a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/wealth/invest/cryptocurrencies-are-risky-but-can-be-rewarding-risks-to-know-how-to-make-the-most-of-the-opportunity/articleshow/83457595.cms?from=mdr"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/wealth/invest/cryptocurrencies-are-risky-but-can-be-rewarding-risks-to-know-how-to-make-the-most-of-the-opportunity/articleshow/83457595.cms?from=mdr</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">22  </span><a href="https://cryptochicks.ca/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://cryptochicks.ca/</span></a></p>
<p>References:</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Blockchain Social Media &#8211; Towards User-Controlled Data.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">LeewayHertz</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 22 Sept. 2021, www.leewayhertz.com/blockchain-social-media-platforms/.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Blockchain Use Cases in the Sports and ESports Industry.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ivan on Tech Academy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 12 Mar. 2021, academy.ivanontech.com/blog/blockchain-use-cases-in-the-sports-and-esports-industry. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Blockchain, AI, Programming, Cryptocurrency, Blockchain Business for Women and Youth.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">CryptoChicks</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 14 Sept. 2021, cryptochicks.ca/.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Bringing Blockchain to High School Students.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">BRINGING BLOCKCHAIN TO HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, SIMBA CHAIN, blog.simbachain.com/blog/bringing-blockchain-to-high-school-students.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Digital Identity And Voting Redefined With Blockchain Technology.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain Magazine</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 11 Jan. 2018, blockchainmagazine.net/digital-identity-voting-redefined-blockchain-technology/.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Here&#8217;s How to Protect Your Art If Someone Makes It an NFT &#8211; CoinDesk.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">CoinDesk Latest Headlines RSS</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 17 Mar. 2021, www.coindesk.com/stop-tokenizing-art-you-dont-own.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Humenansky, Justine CFA. “The Impact of Digital Identity.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Medium</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Blockchain at Berkeley, 16 Aug. 2019, medium.com/blockchain-at-berkeley/the-impact-of-digital-identity-9eed5b0c3016.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stephen, Bijan. “NFT Mania Is Here, and so Are the Scammers.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Verge</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, The Verge, 20 Mar. 2021, www.theverge.com/2021/3/20/22334527/nft-scams-artists-opensea-rarible-marble-cards-fraud-art.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/blockchain-in-real-life-for-regular-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>With Everything That&#8217;s Happened This Year&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/with-everything-thats-happened-this-year/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/with-everything-thats-happened-this-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 12:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.building-u.com/?p=4031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Strange times we are living in. There has been a lot of speculation about what life after Covid will look like. Would it be exactly like life as we knew it without Covid? Would there be lingering effects in how we behave and interact, in what we prefer, in what will succeed or fail or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strange times we are living in. There has been a lot of speculation about what life after Covid will look like. Would it be exactly like life as we knew it without Covid? Would there be lingering effects in how we behave and interact, in what we prefer, in what will succeed or fail or emerge in the marketplace, or in how we each choose to move through life? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We created a simple survey at a time right before the start of the vaccine rollout to try to answer these questions by getting some insight into Pre v. Post-Covid interest and comfort levels around some of the more fundamental and ubiquitous activities of everyday life: social gathering, dating, shopping, and travel. The 162 survey participants, though random and varied in terms of age and country of residence, were all more significantly represented through gender and length of lockdown.</span></p>
<p><b>SOCIAL GATHERING:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">So as they say, let’s get into it. “With everything that’s happened this year…” is possibly the most commonly heard pandemic modifier used to universally convey the negative impact of Covid-19 on whatever piece of everyday life is inserted immediately after. No matter where you live on planet Earth, Covid-19 restrictions during the past year entirely changed the landscape of social events. It normalized not only social isolation, but also public shame and criminal penalties for violating it. In this portion of our survey, we tried to get an idea of how comfortable people thought they would be post pandemic in smaller (50 or less) social gatherings with people they knew v. larger ones (more than 50) with people they didn’t know. We broke this down even further to look at whether their prospective comfort level changed if the gathering was held indoors or outdoors. It is important to note that we conducted our survey over one week in May 2021, when US restrictions had not yet been lifted, when Canada was still in lockdown, and when India was experiencing a dramatic and debilitating second wave.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the results showing all groups’ apprehension around the prospect of attending larger indoor gatherings with strangers matched our general expectations, we were surprised that our survey data suggested a considerable percent of 15-18 year olds would be “much less comfortable” attending indoor social gatherings with 50+ people &#8212; especially in contrast to the “Florida Teen” spring break news stories covering the thousands of “insensitive delinquents” partying in Miami in a pandemic. Teen caution carried over to large outdoor gatherings as well, where 25% of respondents still answered “much less comfortable”, compared to 0 respondents for those 31 and over. Results were similar for small indoor events as for large outdoor events: “slightly less comfortable” remained the dominant response. However in this scenario, a small number of the 31 and over group were apparently a bit more uncomfortable, creeping back into the much less comfortable category. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether this is more a reflection of the difference in the types of outdoor 50+ outdoor gatherings envisioned by respondents in each age group (raucous jammed outdoor concerts vs. neighbourhood barbecues), or whether 15-18 year olds are just a bit more cautious and compliant, we can’t really say from our results. We can say that since the time of this survey, re-opening has become a reality, at least in the US, and the general anecdotal consensus would seem to indicate far less apprehension than results of this fairly recent survey had forecast. What seems to be clear is that people adapt. And what we seem to be witnessing is the effects of people emerging from “reconfiguring their lives around the constraints of Covid”&#8230;but free from peer and social pressure.”(This is) where we end up seeing a lot of habit change, and the formation of new habits…(as people) reconsider the life they had prior (to Covid restrictions).”</span></p>
<p><b>DATING:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Social distancing, and no social gathering was definitely one of the ”constraints of Covid” for nearly everyone. This changed the social interaction landscape for not only group gatherings but also for dating&#8211; effectively eliminating the option for the type and degree of physical proximity traditionally associated with starting, maintaining, and growing intimate relationships. Given the pre-pandemic inundation of dating apps, advertisers’ propensities to use sex to sell products, and our historical and cultural predisposition to prioritize romantic attraction, it could seem that losing the opportunity for this type of intimacy would be pretty devastating. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not so, according to our survey. Although there were some small notable observations regarding online v. in-person preference &#8212; i.e. that men were more interested in dating in general and in meeting a date in person than women, and that more older respondents “31-and-over” had less interest in meeting people in-person, while more younger respondents “15-to-18” had less interest in meeting people online than they did pre-Covid &#8212; our survey showed a clear majority of “no change” in dating interest across age, gender, and pretty much every length of lockdown. These results would seem to be corroborated by a recent study on loneliness conducted by UCLA professor of social psychology, Naomi Eisenberger, “The most intense experiences we have in our closest social relationships include feeling loved, connected and wanting to help other people.” Using data collected through 2020 around the nature of meaningful close social relationships and whether they can in fact be established in the course of a pandemic, she determines that feeling safe &#8212; as in connected and not rejected or left out, is a big part of what defines a meaningful close social relationship&#8211; and that they can indeed be created, even in isolation during a pandemic. She also offers insights into how they are established and maintained. “We’ve seen that having social support — whether through romantic relationships, parent-child relationships or friendships — can make the world seem safer….” So quite possibly we just missed the mark by defining intimacy much too narrowly? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">  Small personal interactions do matter and have been missed. From awkward elevator rides, to late night gas station chats: people across the globe lost out on a lot of these small, yet crucial daily interactions that physically produce serotonin and emotionally just kept you going. Regardless of how directly or indirectly the virus itself impacted individuals or their loved ones, people everywhere were “facing isolation, boredom, and the need for small joy.” This would seem to be the kind of intimate meaningful connection that people seek &#8212; the small in-person moments of seeing grandparents, and new babies, and sisters, and cousins, and best friends. But apparently there can be small online moments as well: according to the same UCLA study mentioned above, and similarly reflected in the status quo results of our own small survey, “Whether you’re living alone or with other people doesn’t really affect (your feelings of feeling safe and connected). What does seem to have an effect is subjective isolation, or how lonely you feel.. It turns out that your objective situation doesn’t matter as much as what you do with it.” </span></p>
<p><b>SHOPPING:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Successful shopping, on the other hand, is much less subjective and more dependent on your objective situation. In-person shopping was one of the many commercial casualties of Covid-19; Online shopping enjoyed a new nearly universal prominence as not merely a convenient option or safer alternative, but as THE only access to certain goods. In our survey we set out to learn whether peoples’ preferences for types of shopping changed from pre-Covid times to the time of our survey (April 2021)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The results were probably not that shocking: a large portion of respondents across all periods of lockdown responded “no change” for both preference for in-person and online shopping. There were, however, a few interesting differences of note. First, It was only respondents who had experienced lockdown for 1-3 months who said they had more interest rather than less interest in in-person shopping in anticipation for post pandemic life. Every other group across all levels of lockdown had less interest in the prospect of post pandemic  in-person shopping. As for preference for online shopping, our results showed that  more interest in online shopping  surpassed no change only  for those in lockdown for 1-3 months or over a year. For those in lockdown for that ‘mid-range’ of 4-6 months or 7-12 months, no change was the most recorded response.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Something that might be contributing to the high incidence of “no change” is that there might be other factors influencing how people shop and what they choose to shop for beyond simply that they can’t go outside right now. As Dhani Mau writes on Yahoo Life, “shoppers are also now being influenced by a number of factors not related to the shelter-in-place lifestyle — like whether a brand&#8217;s founder had been exposed for racist behavior, or how a designer responded to police brutality, or if a deal is too good to pass up.”  The additional time people have or had, and have on their own, during quarantine is allowing them to make more thoughtful decisions&#8211;  decisions that come from their own preferences and priorities as opposed to ones that are driven by external social, professional, or peer pressures. This more considered and personal decision-making approach seemed to carry-over into traveling preferences as well.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><b><br />
TRAVEL:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">From the beginning of the pandemic, Covid-19 profoundly affected travel; as airports closed and governments mandated stay-at-home lockdowns, traveling—aside from perhaps walking to a local store—became nearly impossible. In our survey, we sought to analyze whether the pandemic altered people’s interest and comfort level surrounding different types of  travel. We looked at traveling for pleasure, air travel, local land travel, long-distance travel for pleasure, and long-distance travel for work; we also asked how the requirement of a vaccine passport would impact their interest in international air travel. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We found several intriguing outcomes in the data. First, when looking at gender groups, females appeared to be less interested on average than males in traveling for pleasure, air travel, and long-distance travel for work, a result from our survey that saw correspondence with a survey taken by Forbes where they concluded: “women felt less confident throughout the travel journey than men”. Another interesting result we found was that people had mostly no change in their interest for land travel, regardless of gender and age group. Many people answered that their interest had increased, and very few said their interest in land travel “slightly” decreased. There were similar outcomes in regards to the responses around whether requiring a vaccine passport would change people’s desire to travel. “No change” led the way as the most popular response, with  “increase interest” following behind as a close second. Very few people answered that the requirement of a vaccine passport would hinder their interest. Although the interest in travel seemed unchanged, how people are travelling and what they are focussing on has definitely been impacted by both Covid-19 and by the experience of lockdown. According to Euronews travel, there seems to be a variety of shifts in the choices people make around travel: whether closer to home or closer to nature, more luxuriously or more sustainably, more with family or with more friends. Having more time at home to think about where we want to be when we don’t have to be at home seems to have made us all clearer about travel. It’s less that there is any trend toward one particular type of travel, and more that the trend is a consistent post Covid perspective shift towards more consciously chosen, priority aligned, planned travel.   </span></p>
<p><b>IN THE END:<br />
</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">While we learned a lot from devising survey questions and identifying trends from distilling the results &#8211;we recognize that all this information is a lot to process, and begs the question: what can we do with what we’ve learned? Our particular approach to recording peoples’ post Covid predictions about their relative interest and comfort level doing just a few essential activities of day to day life, may give some small insights on interest and comfort level, but it left big gaps around the ways people’s choices changed and the reasons behind them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As people in countries with widespread vaccine rollout return relatively quickly and smoothly to what seems surprisingly normal, it can possibly appear that we’re all pretty resilient and the effects of Covid are not long-lasting at all. Over time it will become clearer how COVID-19  affects how we communicate with each other, live our lives, and the level of caution we exercise in performing tasks we may have done casually and fearlessly prior to the pandemic. According to an article by Anderson which focuses on the new normal in 2025 post-pandemic, experts predict that by the year 2025, as a global community we can expect to see increased reliance on digital tools due to our desire for convenience and safety as well as a world where the broad adoption of “remote processes&#8221; (working from home, virtual schooling, e-commerce etc.) continues to grow. But just as the predictive answers respondents gave to this survey just over a month ago may be quite different from their answers today, predictions can be difficult and are just predictions. What we can say for sure is that ”with everything that’s happened this year”,  this uninvited solitary time out of our daily routine that forced us all to consider and reconsider what we really want or need, how and why we do things, and who we want to do them with, was definitely not all bad.  </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">References</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anderson, J., Rainie, L., &amp; Vogels, E. A. (2021, April 05). Experts Say the &#8216;New Normal&#8217; in 2025 Will Be Far More Tech-Driven, Presenting More Big Challenges. Retrieved from https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/2021/02/18/experts-say-the-new-normal-in-2025-will-be-far-more-tech-driven-presenting-more-big-challenges/</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eisenberger, N., ’97, M.A. ’00, Ph.D. ’05,. (2021, June 11). Is One Really the Loneliest Number? (B. Wright, Ed.). Retrieved from https://newsroom.ucla.edu/magazine/naomi-eisenberger-loneliness-pandemic-relationships</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kholkar, S. (2021, April 26). Post-Pandemic travel trends: Armed with vaccine certificates, tourists wait to undertake revenge travel. Retrieved from https://www.financialexpress.com/lifestyle/travel-tourism/post-pandemic-travel-trends-armed-with-vaccine-certificates-tourists-wait-to-undertake-revenge-travel/2240353/</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mau, D. (2021, June 9). As People Move Out of Big Cities, Fashion Retail Follows. Retrieved from https://www.yahoo.com/lifestyle/people-move-big-cities-fashion-120000897.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuYmluZy5jb20v&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAGQy_ryWMrrJasxRYCFe0hIwYQ-L2gVwjGXC18vPeIQMCLDM-d53HHnjPtYK6Y-csWBXM0eMk0x_eAGya-hNcjOiAjgjflMoCD9qMxstS7GQMlJGkJCUdhM-atW-VE-wdAQNFVwvcGjrv814LmFqcVu80KogQMep8hx-TV5G6hKx</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palmer, S. (2021, May 12). Glampervans and the death of mini-breaks: All the 2021 travel trends. Retrieved from https://www.euronews.com/travel/2021/05/12/here-s-what-experts-are-forecasting-for-the-travel-industry-in-2021</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/with-everything-thats-happened-this-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;&#8230;but I like them! Who cares who their friends are?&#8217;:        Partners Matter in the Data Collection Game of Pass the Parcel</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/partners-matter-in-the-data-collection-game-of-pass-the-parcel/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/partners-matter-in-the-data-collection-game-of-pass-the-parcel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 04:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.building-u.com/?p=3675</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To use or not to use… an app….that is the decision&#8230;It’s one that many of us arrive at with tremendous conviction backed by an equally tremendous lack of meaningful information, often in the form of some cleverly wordsmithed Tweet or social media post that most of us could do little more than meaninglessly parrot if [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To use or not to use… an app….that is the decision&#8230;It’s one that many of us arrive at with tremendous conviction backed by an equally tremendous lack of meaningful information, often in the form of some cleverly wordsmithed Tweet or social media post that most of us could do little more than meaninglessly parrot if asked to explain. The notion of being able to navigate the indecipherable verbiage of privacy policies and control of your own personal information on the internet independently is inconceivable. In fact, our relationship with data collection and privacy policies can probably best be described as “akrasia” a relatively uncommon but in this instance relevant term for individuals who act against their better judgement because of a lack of will. We are resigned to scrolling as numbly and nimbly as possible to the only word we can be sure we will recognize and understand, “AGREE” where we quickly place an x and click to reach the holy grail &#8212; immediate access.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is especially true in the realm of data collection where consent is implied or assumed and where the same people who have energy and tools to bargain with the customer service representative at Walmart stand befuddled and unarmed when looking to address perceived violations or concerns with the company that simultaneously has access to their bank information and universal log-in credentials…. And this is just around the violations and concerns they actually know about! What about  those they don’t?  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To address our general lack of understanding paired with our (initial) general lack of concern around rampant unchecked data collection and unintelligible privacy policies, we invited author, educator, speaker, and renowned cyber security genius Claudiu Popa to an open discussion. We wanted to learn whether it’s indeed possible for mere mortals (like us) to understand and control what is happening with our own personal data. Beyond that, we wanted to know, “where are we headed?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, to begin, we were given some good reason to possibly rethink our cavalier “who cares if we have nothing to hide” stance on data collection, and that we must &#8212; not just should &#8212; care about who has our information and how it is being used, because we, the consumers, have the most to lose. Despite the clear evidence that we would all prefer to cross our fingers, close our eyes, and take our chances than read a privacy policy, our conversation revealed just how important they are, and just how crucial it is that we read them. A company&#8217;s privacy policy on their website explains which of your data that company has access to, and how it can use it. It would then seem to follow that if you trust a company (let’s say FritO Lay because who doesn&#8217;t love chips), then you would think it’s okay to give them (FritO lay) access to your data, since after all, you already “know” them and love their potato chips! But maybe, not so fast!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Privacy policies are about assessing the trust you can have in a company through their website &#8212; this can be companies you don&#8217;t know and ones you already know. It likely goes beyond simply assessing the trust you may already have in that particular brand/company (i.e. Frito Lay)) because of your positive and longtime experience with their products or services. Whether you are on a site of a &#8220;trusted&#8221; company that you know or whether you are on an entirely new site, it is important to understand whether the company themselves (Frito Lay, in this case) uses your data exclusively, or whether they share it with anyone else. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can learn this through scanning their privacy policy for important keywords &#8212; ones that validate continued  trust or ones that should bring up red flags.  &#8220;EXCEPT&#8221; is one of those words&#8230;in the general context of  &#8216;we don&#8217;t share any of the data we collect here with anyone EXCEPT&#8217; and often followed by the word &#8220;PARTNERS&#8221;&#8230;. What that means is that what you may not have considered is that FritO Lay (your innocent snacking pal) is owned by Pepsico&#8230;oh, and Pepsico also owns Starbucks, Papa John’s, Aunt Jemima Mixes, Quaker Oats,&#8230;err basically a bevy (pun entirely intended) of soft drink companies (Gatorade, Mountain Dew, Crush), and&#8230;well, you get the point. Claudiu shared that often each of these smaller companies share one privacy policy with their parent company. Soooo now, all of a sudden, sharing your personal information with the Frito Lay website has helped BeyondMeat (through the PepsiCo-BeyondMeat partnership) decide whether or not your community’s burger joint should sell plant meat. So then, it&#8217;s not just your friendly snack partner Frito Lay that will have access to your data&#8230;hmmmm It&#8217;s all of their snacking friends, too! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unfortunately this is not even the extent of the tracking and use of your information. To add to the infiltration of your information, companies can use digital advertisements as marketing tools to promote products and services and to collect personal information and data, specifically metadata—which includes your search history, time and location, how long you spend on a website, the links you click, what you download, and what you purchase. To the average consumer, metadata appears insignificant. However, to corporations, metadata illustrates a person’s routine, affiliations, interactions, living style, etc., and allows companies to create a personalized Internet experience for each customer. For instance, applications like Youtube and Netflix often provide users with a recommended list of videos, shows, and ads to click on. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although these examples may seem  like creative, relatively harmless, and even positive use of your data (and so, may not elicit large red flags), consider the data privacy implications of our ubiquitous consent to Google Maps to help us get where we’re going (&#8230;because the art of planning our route through learning it or using an actual map has been long lost).  The information about the route you use to get places becomes a saleable commodity to companies, and when combined with a whole lotta other people’s routes, it provides insights on the best places to potentially build retail outlets and fast food chains. Yikes! TMI&#8230;literally!The upshot, at the end of the day, is your information is worth something and  “partners matter” in evaluating the level of trust you can place on any site requesting your information.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How can you check what companies know about you? On Google Chrome, you can check </span><a href="https://adssettings.google.com/notarget"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Manage Ads Settings</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and turn on Ad Personalization. From there, you will be able to view the list of topics that Google believes you like and gauge how accurately those topics align with your interests and activities. On Facebook, you can download the app’s archive which includes comments, posts, photos, connections you made with other users, and even content that you previously deleted. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To limit the collection of your metadata, you can use ad-blockers. There are several different types of ad blockers including:</span></p>
<p><span class="s1"><b>1. </b></span><span class="s2"><b>Virtual Peer Networks (VPNs): </b>VPNs can protect you from multiple kinds of tracking. A VPN directs your device’s data       traffic through a chosen private server rather than your internet service provider (ISP). This redirection of your data effectively       hides your IP address—the numerical label your ISP gives your device—and prevents third-party trackers from pinpointing             your location.<br />
<b></b></span><b></b><span class="s2"><b>2. Browser Add-ons and Extensions: </b>Extensions on chrome like AdBlock, uBlock, Privacy Badger, Ghostery prevent advertisements from appearing as you search the web. They can also show you the particular “invaders” on a particular website who have access to your visit and interest in both the information you share and ways you interact on that site.<b><br />
</b></span><b></b><span class="s2"><b>3. Tor: </b>This is a free software that enables anonymous communication like a VPN. Tor directs internet traffic through an onion network where messages are enveloped in layers of encryption akin to the layers of an onion. Ultimately, this software conceals your location and internet usage from trackers and anyone conducting network surveillance and traffic analysis. <b><br />
</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Certainly the overwhelming evidence points to the fact that the onus for protecting our information and controlling access to it, is currently on us, the consumer, rather than on  corporations or  governments. Traditional laws involving privacy have consistently been built against the consumer with no penalty to companies that are negligent with user data. Canada and the United States specifically have had historically outdated and nonexistent data protection regulations: in fact, even today, the United States does not consider data privacy a universal right. The significance of this gaping oversight and its need to be addressed affects everyone’s internet usage as well as how the internet itself operates. It’s the reason that Ad Blockers, VPNs, and other protection software have become so popularized in the last few years. Until governments step in and recognize data and data privacy as a universal right, consumers will continue to rely on third parties to keep themselves secure online. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is hope for change however, as more countries are adopting legislation that will force companies to invest more in technology built for data protection and transparency. The DPA (Data Protection Act) now forces Canadian companies to disclose to all clients any potential and ongoing data breaches. Before the DPA was established in Canada, Canadian corporations essentially had no reason to prioritize protecting user privacy. This need to prioritize user privacy has led to an increase in establishing effective cyber security, a trend that is consistent with the pace of many countries adopting similar legislation, if not quite “cutting edge”. One of the strongest current sets of data collection and privacy regulations is the one created by the European Union (EU); the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) spells out the specifics of personal information that can be collected on residents of any of the EU’s 28 member states. According to this new privacy policy, personal data is regarded to be information that either is associated with an ‘identified’ or ‘identifiable living individual.’  Because the definition itself is fairly vague, corporations have to be extra cautious in order to avoid inadvertently violating its mandates. Although the GDPR is aimed at protecting EU citizens’ privacy protection rights, the globalized nature of the internet and corporations means that almost any company with any sort of international profile will eventually be compelled to take notice and upgrade the understandability of the privacy policy it puts forth to users, and transparency around the data it collects from them. The GDPR is characterized by the three following principles:</span></p>
<p><strong>1. </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Direct, informed consent is a requirement for companies to acquire user data.<br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>2. </strong>Data must only be collected if it is directly related to the company’s products and how it operates. This requires businesses to make significant changes to their user interfaces to give consumers more control over how their data is being collected and used.<br />
<strong>3. </strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Explicit parental consent is mandatory for those under the age of 16.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Negligence is punishable by steep penalties, which can amount to up to 4% of the yearly profit of the liable company. As Claudiu further explains, at this point in Canada, responsibility still falls only moderately on corporations to ensure there is no negligence regarding privacy, but transparency is an important first step. Disclosing the use of collected data is still a murky process built to protect companies first and foremost, but Canadians can now use the privacy commissioner to file complaints or even flat out call for a deletion of their data if they feel that the company was negligent with their information. The law requires that companies comply with this. Canadian companies no longer ‘own’ your data, so users can utilize the privacy commissioner as an aggregator to help with the enforceability of the law. When companies are forced by law to acknowledge the ethical aspect of privacy and see that it can affect their bottom line, they increase the care and sensitivity around how they collect and manage user data in order to avoid the financial and commercial consequences for breaches.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the end of the day, how does this all really affect you? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The prospect of  reading Apple or Microsoft&#8217;s seventeen page long privacy policy every time you update a software or download an application will probably still seem like a cumbersome and pointless task, since, let’s face it, you’re going to check the box &#8212; so ultimately you will still get access and they will still get information. The idea is not to ‘NOT interact’ or somehow be afraid of interacting, but more just to s-l-l-l-o-w the whole process down.  There are good reasons, and easy ways, to know the names of  companies’ “partnering friends” or websites’ “uninvited guests” involved in this internet game of Pass the Parcel. To paraphrase our overwhelmingly favourite takeaway from the discussion with Claudiu, “the opposite of security is convenience”. In a world where access to information gets faster and easier, and information gets more time consuming to look at and harder to decipher, it becomes routine to prioritize convenience over security &#8212; and ignore or justify this choice as simply the cost of having access to everything always. The reality is we can all be confident and clear about if and how we choose to interact on sites and why. It just takes a little more time.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>References</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Iwrin, L. (July 30, 2020). </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The GDPR: Understanding the 6 data protection principles. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">it Governance. </span><a href="https://www.itgovernance.eu/blog/en/the-gdpr-understanding-the-6-data-protection-principles"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.itgovernance.eu/blog/en/the-gdpr-understanding-the-6-data-protection-principles</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nicole, O. (January 5, 2021).</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Minors and Your Privacy Policy. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Privacy Policies.<br />
</span><a href="https://www.privacypolicies.com/blog/minors-privacy-policy/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.privacypolicies.com/blog/minors-privacy-policy/</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Porup, J.M. (October 15, 2019). </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is the Tor Browser? And how it can help protect your </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">identity. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">CSO. </span><a href="https://www.csoonline.com/article/3287653/what-is-the-tor-browser-how-it-works-and-how-it-can-help-you-protect-your-identity-online.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.csoonline.com/article/3287653/what-is-the-tor-browser-how-it-works-and-how-it-can-help-you-protect-your-identity-online.html</span></a></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Protect your privacy: How Ad Blockers can protect your privacy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. (April 15, 2019). Tapmydata. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Retrieved April 2021. </span><a href="https://tapmydata.com/protect-your-privacy-how-ad-blockers-can-protect-your-privacy/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://tapmydata.com/protect-your-privacy-how-ad-blockers-can-protect-your-privacy/</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wadell, K. (June 3, 2015). </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The NSA&#8217;s Bulk Collection Is Over, but Google and Facebook Are Still </span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">in the Data Business. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Atlantic.<br />
</span><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2015/06/the-nsas-bulk-collection-is-over-but-google-and-facebook-are-still-in-the-data-business/458496/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2015/06/the-nsas-bulk-collection-is-over-but-google-and-facebook-are-still-in-the-data-business/458496/</span></a></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is VPN? How It Works, Types of VPN. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(n.d.) kaspersky. Retrieved April 2020.<br />
</span><a href="https://www.kaspersky.com/resource-center/definitions/what-is-a-vpn"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.kaspersky.com/resource-center/definitions/what-is-a-vpn</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wolford, B. (2020). </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are the GDPR Fines? </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">GDPR. </span><a href="https://gdpr.eu/fines/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://gdpr.eu/fines/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.torproject.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.torproject.org/</span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/partners-matter-in-the-data-collection-game-of-pass-the-parcel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LET&#8217;S START WITH DINNER: A Red Riding Hood Approach to Getting Acquainted with Wolf of Wall Street Investing</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/lets-start-with-dinner/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/lets-start-with-dinner/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 17:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Academics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.building-u.com/?p=3379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The GameStop spike could be described as a complex lottery of big winners, and big losers. To some, the unforeseeable yet recurring turn of events was empowering. However, for most the stock market became even more daunting and seemingly unpredictable. Though some rejoice when the topic of investing eases its way into conversation, many more [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The GameStop spike could be described as a complex lottery of big winners, and big losers. To some, the unforeseeable yet recurring turn of events was empowering. However, for most the stock market became even more daunting and seemingly unpredictable. Though some rejoice when the topic of investing eases its way into conversation, many more shrivel with agony as the term finds another way to seep into a list of worries. Conversations about investing are often uncomfortable and can feel like know-it-all challenges in a game where you didn&#8217;t get the directions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As students who are constantly tasked with learning about different fields, we thought it was interesting to note that Coding as a subject&#8230;equally difficult and obtuse with certainly as many or more facets as finance…with probably fewer applications to real life than finance&#8230; does not elicit the same resistance. People of all levels of knowledge and interest flock to learn basics or learn more about coding, join random hackathons, and seem to regard whatever they learn or get from however they involve themselves as a fun win/win. Why is there such a large disconnect with finance, and how can it be made more accessible and inviting? We decided to investigate these disconnects and misunderstandings and offer some ways to bridge the gap between wanting to invest and feeling comfortable doing it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To that end, we held an open conversation with multi-portfolio professional finance experts, who shared the surprising realities of what investing looks like, and the true weight that context and time, even more than specific investments, hold on meeting our expectations for high financial returns. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When talking about investment, one of the first hurdles to clear is the misplaced notion that saving money is simply “safer” risk-free investing. Although these terms are frequently used interchangeably, investment and savings are as different as chalk and cheese. And before even jumping onto the pits and pearls of investment v. saving, it’s important to add in and become more familiar with the term “inflation”&#8211; a word that is thrown around a lot in casual conversation, with little clear understanding of how it impacts our personal saving strategies for future financial security.   Here’s a quick question:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">$5 million right now or $1 million each year over the next 5 years ?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you chose the latter, chances are that you’re among the large portion of people who’ve left out the role of inflation. According to the Oxford dictionary, inflation is simply “a general increase in prices and fall in the purchasing value of money.” Using the previous example, this means that the value of $1 million dollars is likely to depreciate 5 to 10 years down the line. Given that, the right choice is $5 million right now. Let’s take an example with a smaller amount, say you’ve kept aside $200 from your salary/gifts, and instead of investing you save it (keep it to yourself). Next year, if there’s an inflation of 5% you’re likely to be at a loss because the value of $200 has now reduced. In contrast, if you invest your money at a yield of 10% you’re likely to make a profit of $10 in the same scenario. That’s what people mean when they say “Money has time value” &#8212; and according to one of our invited experts, it is</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">THE most important financial takeaway for any student.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In order to stay ahead of the curve, your savings and income have to grow faster than inflation, or else you’re likely to incur a loss in the long run. Hence it is important to invest in places that can beat inflation. This can be done through multiple methods:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In reality, beating inflation can be as simple as you’d like it to be. If saving suits your “comfortability”, then maybe just setting aside an additional 2.00% (which is about the current inflation rate in Canada) of the amount you had planned to save, will do the trick. If having to do this is daunting, but still worth acting  on&#8211;there are even more options. Roth IRA’s (Individual Retirement Account), and the Canadian equivalent, TFSAs (Tax Free Savings Account), were two, very low risk entry points into investing recommended to us by our  financial expert guests. Both of these options are popular due to their intrinsically stable structure, favorable tax treatment, and myriad of investment options to best suit individual savings goals and risk tolerance. For everyone&#8217;s sake, that’s as far as we will go with specifics: however, it does not hurt to know that these accounts are the professionals’ choice as solid long-term options. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From our discussion, we also learned that although there are two obvious giant options for investing: investing yourself, or having professionals (brokers) invest for you, there are actually all different shades and levels within these two options and they are entirely possible for you to understand and compare. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s consider a familiar scenario to shed some light on your capability. Consider you’re having some friends over for dinner and need to buy food for the occasion. Depending on when you invited them/ how much time you have, how much interest you have in selecting and preparing the menu items (all things that you thoughtfully or casually exercised some preference in choosing), you will have options that can serve those choices.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Without some serious expertise or interest or preference in spending your time researching, you may not select buying “every” item individually from wherever they come from originally, but instead may rely on the items in/ selected by one or more grocery stores.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loosely, the different scenarios that you consider every day for grocery shopping can be used to illustrate various automated investing or “Robo-Investing” options (which is not actually investing done by robots&#8211;though, yes, that initially crossed our minds). For instance, say you choose to use an online delivery service for the groceries for dinner. In this scenario, you set out a list of what you want generally (dinner), but you are not allowed to specify the exact items, the brands, or the quality</span><b>;</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> just what kind of dinner party (maybe level of formality) you are generally looking to have for x-amount of dollars. As you expect,</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and are clear about</span><b>&#8212;</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">you will know whether there are any costs associated with the service and the delivery or whether it’s free, so in this scenario you can specify what you generally want (dinner) and how much you are looking to spend, but you have no specific input over what will arrive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can also opt to change the scenario slightly</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and specifically request things for your dinner like chicken, fish, beef, or vegan chili. We can equate this to various “securities” (the overarching category for “stuff” you can invest in and trade) being your dinner choice. A preference for chicken can resemble</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">a preference for stocks/bonds (the value or debt of specific companies)</span><b>.</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">preference for fish</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">can</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">be likened to a preference for Index Funds (generally highly regarded basket of stocks). A</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">preference for beef can reflect a preference for an ETF (Exchange Traded Funds&#8211;a bit of a new and improved version of an Index Fund). And a preference for a vegan option can represent a preference for SRI (Socially Responsible Investing)&#8230;.and, yes, that’s an actual thing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like the chicken, fish, beef, or vegan chili between brands at one grocery store or between the same brands at different grocery stores, prices and quality will vary</span><b>. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just as with this selection of foods, people’s preferences and reasons for selecting investing in a group of stocks /bonds v. an Index Fund v. Exchange Traded Fund v. SRI will be different as well</span><b>. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though these may</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">seem like unnecessarily complicated terminology and glib acronyms tied to confusing concepts that you feel you will never remember, there are numbers of perfectly accessible ways for anyone to functionally understand them. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If we continue the shopping-for-your-dinner-with-friends grocery analogy, let’s say you’d prefer your friendly knowledgeable butcher to pick out the best meat and best cut. As you might expect, that might come with a small surcharge.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">And what about cutting/preparing your beef in a special way</span><b>, </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">a little more cost, right? Well this is like having an advisor, and in most places that comes with a fee, though also in some places at some level, this service could be free.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Say you’ve learned a bit about meat recently and have been looking into how to select and cut it properly so you want to give it a go. Cross your fingers; doing it alone, could certainly be a better than average experience given all of your prep: but there is the chance of “butchering” the job or your fingers, which would be a bit of a downer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We understand and totally empathize with the fact that even when you know that it’s probably better to invest your money, and even when you have some idea that there are alternatives available to you and that you will likely be able to grasp them , there can still be some big things that get in the way. Investing intrinsically has a Risk/ Reward structure, meaning over time, taking higher risks can be expected to generate higher returns, but may also lead to greater losses. This is where things can start to run amok, since sometimes we only seem to hear/ focus on either  “may lead to greater losses” (which means high-tailing it right out of this conversation!) or “can be expected to generate higher returns” (yes! time to join WallStreetBets and open a Robin Hood account!), instead of considering both together. Risk and Reward exist together, as part of the same scenario, and so, always need to be considered together. This “considering together” is determining your “risk tolerance” which can then be used to inform a comfortable personal financial plan.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But assessing and feeling comfortable with your risk tolerance is definitely one of those things that “gets in the way”. Quite frankly, just the phrase “risk tolerance” itself is scary and distancing. The scariness is then compounded by (the perception of) the fact that the most reassuring path to better understanding your personal financial risk tolerance will involve speaking to an investment professional. Yikes! The prospect of speaking with overly solicitous or overtly disinterested, fast talking, or slow-talking experts using unfamiliar acronyms, terminology and concepts, and drawing attention to how little money you have with how little you know, is about as inviting as scheduling a root canal. Just to reference quickly back to coding: there is no scary, required assessment of tolerance for strange symbolic math language, and  the small degree of enlightenment you need for your very basic understanding at any time can usually be found in seconds in very plain and relatable language from your friend, or your friend’s friend messaging while taking a break from gaming in their basement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our expert guests guided us over this hump by recommending some financial sites and platforms highly regarded for smooth and easy entry into the intimidating world of investing: </span><a href="https://www.wealthfront.com/investing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wealthfront</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.betterment.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Betterment</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> were their recommended standouts. We checked them out as well (for friendliness!) and came across some others (</span><a href="https://www.wealthsimple.com/en-ca/?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;keyword=wealthsimple&amp;matchtype=e&amp;network=g&amp;device=c&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiA7YyCBhD_ARIsALkj54rBs2Rco4gHnmIOKs53GN6AZgnOJMOHtfM9S1jaQ2K_c2hovbX3Q3kaAn9lEALw_wcB"><span style="font-weight: 400;">WealthSimple</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.sofi.com/our-story/?__cf_chl_jschl_tk__=91b74fbbe3cbd2e68795c70f5ea3a1418e769654-1615089618-0-AX7bunUg0E3oBXlKASP_EU_EiFo9VsOBT4gHUxKAjLsa9fWiDQUlBRGe1O3Lv8FxJID2IMuTwX-GCtfMWz0D1quYxGfhQeUVzU7Ry_MeLWjUScjlA5FWph2bbQDmBZMe6T7D2lCE8y_EOxrdgjFAEkzPqVem2oBYjUvTI-ocePMT_HS4I3qjSZc5o9ivtAcHpHx4K07hIEDGqZdQ7PfulIqKKvM9jWLqVS4YkV_y4_d-pN9hcqiQsjMtz2JC77wti5OypzWTGIGpecd1nmkKZj9GoNILN5v--SxZbQ2gKPbtibC0zOKlxLRUSExJfEvRxbYldnCEyelvlMXUx6W65WUIVMXPLXSGWzmBp9iTPJLALk_oeZWlAn7oJ6P0CCegMKLXlSySobj_ePt_NePsryo"><span style="font-weight: 400;">SoFi)</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> … along with some </span><a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/investing/betterment-vs-wealthfront-vs-wealthsimple/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">comparison articles</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from </span><a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/reviews/investing/advisors/sofi-automated-investing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NerdWallet</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">! Of Course, there can be other platforms, and of course you might have your own thoughts on this already, but providing clear and simple alternatives for understandable information while identifying comfortable next steps is our goal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And speaking of goals for understandable information, here&#8217;s our plain-speak snapshot of some of the more broadly applicable lingo and acronyms we discussed, on the chance it’s helpful (or at least to know that we didn’t know either!):</span></p>
<p><b>Securities</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are all of the varying things people trade; it includes all of the things mentioned here plus an interminably long list of stuff not mentioned here like real estate, bitcoin, gold, commodities… you get the point.</span></p>
<p><b>Stocks</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><b>Bonds</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are terms frequently used together so it sometimes seems like they’re the same thing, when they’re more like the yin and yang of the same “thing” or company. The company’s total value (how much someone would buy the company for) minus any debt it has is the company’s net value or </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">EQUITY</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Buying a portion (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">SHARE</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">) of a company’s equity is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">STOCK</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and buying a portion of a company’s debt is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">BONDS</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Already, it’s easy to see that personally buying shares of either </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">STOCKS</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">BONDS</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> individually (similar to the dinner ingredients) will require some time, research, and knowledge.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><b>Mutual Funds</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">/</span><b>Index Funds</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">/</span><b>ETFs</b> <b>(Exchange Traded Funds)</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are all just different terms for bundles of companies assembled by professionals. Mutual Funds are bundles of different securities that can be individually assembled and reassembled and traded by a financial expert personally, and so are considered </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">ACTIVE</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><b>Index Funds</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><b>ETF’s (Exchange Traded Funds)</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are similar to mutual funds (bundles of securities), but they are NOT actively managed by individuals, and so they are considered PASSIVE funds. Securities (the varying things people trade) in these funds are all from one particular INDEX (i.e. DOW JONES, S&amp;P 500, S&amp;P/TSX, NASDAQ, etc.); they are assembled according to different goals and strategies by financial investment companies, and they rise or sink in value as a group according to what is happening with the index they are part of. Consider cars (or companies) on a highway (or in an INDEX) losing time as a group (because time is value) when the highway is jammed up, or all the cars gaining time when the highway is clear/doing well.  ETFs simply have more flexible leeway around when they can be traded. </span></p>
<p><b>SRI (Socially Responsible Investing)</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><b>ESG (Environmental, Social and Governance Data) </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">are securities initiatives that fall into &#8220;designated parameters&#8221; (this is the messy part because they are sort of arbitrarily designated parameters) that meet social or environmental good. They can be individual securities in individual companies or the can be groups of securities bundled together in any of the above mentioned structures.We include it because its existence may be surprising (it was to us!), and it can impact people’s comfort with investigating investing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the end of the day, these were our big, general, useful takeaways: Investing can be comfortable. There are levels of preference you can input. It can be lower risk or higher risk. Don’t be afraid to just look around. Like trying to figure out where to get a credit card or deciding what phone plan to buy, platforms and jargon can be complicated and off-putting, but there are always understandable ways to evaluate your options. The more you understand about the inner-workings of the plan, the more bang for your buck. As our experts stressed, money has time value. Similarly, there is value in investing your time in exploring some very navigable options for investing, so that your foray into these unfamiliar waters can be on your terms&#8211; gingerly dipping in a toe,  gently wading into the water, or quite confidently taking the plunge. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><b>Huge Thanks to our Special Guests for this Discussion</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jennifer Turchetta  &#8230; Risk Management&#8230;Morgan Stanley</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jennifer-turchetta-41042139/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.linkedin.com/in/jennifer-turchetta-41042139/</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andy Weng… Financial Educator&#8230;How Money Works/ Wealth Wave<br />
</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/buildingentrepreneurs/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.linkedin.com/in/buildingentrepreneurs/</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Peter Baldwin&#8230; Fractional CFO/ Financial Strategist and Coach<br />
</span><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/baldwinpeter/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.linkedin.com/in/baldwinpeter/</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Todd Turchetta… Portfolio Manager/General Partner&#8230; TGT Capital Management Inc</span></p>
<p>Daniel Melander… Investment Advisor&#8230; Transamerica Financial Advisors<br />
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielmelander/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.linkedin.com/in/danielmelander/</span></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><b>Reference(s)</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">O’Shea, A. (January 13, 2021). </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What Is Socially Responsible Investing (SRI) and How to Get </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Started. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">NerdWallet.  </span><a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/investing/socially-responsible-investing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/investing/socially-responsible-investing</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Voigt, K. (October 28, 2020).</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> How Betterment, Wealthfront and Wealthsimple Compare. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">NerdWallet.<br />
</span><a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/investing/betterment-vs-wealthfront-vs-wealthsimple/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/investing/betterment-vs-wealthfront-vs-wealthsimple/</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Voigt, K. (March 5, 2021). </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">SoFi Automated Investing Review 2021: Pros, Cons and How It </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Compares. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">NerdWallet. </span><a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/reviews/investing/advisors/sofi-automated-investing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.nerdwallet.com/reviews/investing/advisors/sofi-automated-investing</span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/lets-start-with-dinner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WHAT IS THE SECRET TO HAPPINESS?</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/what-is-the-secret-to-happiness/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/what-is-the-secret-to-happiness/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 20:17:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Academics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.building-u.com/?p=3155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is the secret to happiness? Everyone has heard this tired and tried cliche time and time again, but that question wouldn’t be so common if we had an answer. Happiness is subjective, so there isn’t exactly a formula we can use to help make people happier. We do however, have statistics detailing which countries, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">What is the secret to happiness? Everyone has heard this tired and tried cliche time and time again, but that question wouldn’t be so common if we had an answer. Happiness is subjective, so there isn’t exactly a formula we can use to help make people happier. We do however, have statistics detailing which countries, if any, tend to foster a happier populace. Using parameters such as health, communication, governance, and social progress, Scandinavian countries like Finland, have uniquely set themselves apart from the rest of the world when it comes to the elusive metric of citizen satisfaction. The U.N’s world happiness report has seen Finland consistently rank at or near the top almost every year, with their neighbours Sweden and Norway often not far behind (Ollila, J. 2019). What exactly do Finland and their friends do to satisfy their citizens&#8217; needs? Starting from the top, nordic countries have used education as a means to enrich the factors listed above. Studying the nordic education system allows us to key in on specifics that  potentially contribute to this capacity for greater social progress, </span><span class="s2">economic stability, general citizen contentment</span><span class="s1">. In general, Scandinavian countries treat education slightly different from the rest of the world. Whereas countries like the USA and the UK are focussed on constant evaluation to uncover distinctively talented individuals, countries like Finland and Sweden are more focussed on ensuring all (or as many) students as possible are able to discover their own independence and autonomy, outside of the classroom. So, what is it about the Finnish (and other nordic) education systems that help build and develop a happier and stable population, and  does it come in a list other countries can copy and paste?</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">We discussed the Scandinavian education system&#8217;s traits with a high school student, Klara Wagenius, from Sweden to gain some personal insight into their educational tenets and practices. Klara confirmed what is commonly believed: that students are given very little homework, experience shorter school hours and are granted longer breaks.  Moreover, the system does not rely mainly on academic results to stream students into different pathways. In fact, streaming is based on interest without much reliance on national test scores. Other countries such as Singapore place a heavy emphasis on grades, streaming students during every step of their pre-tertiary education. </span><span class="s1">The Nordic system&#8217;s flexibility is enviable and serves to sharply contrast the immovable set-in-stone results of systems that use streaming like Singapore where moving to a path or line that is more aligned with a student&#8217;s interests can become challenging to the point of nearly impossible. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">We also learned that beyond the fairly well-known fact that education in Sweden is completely free for its citizens, Swedish high school students are actually paid a grant of $120 to attend school! (Raj, R. 2016). </span><span class="s3">Another  striking “observation” from our chat with Klara was that Swedish schools have well defined periods of break, where students aren’t expected to do school work; this stands in stark contrast to expectations of American students</span><span class="s4">,</span><span class="s1"> who often receive copious summer reading lists, pressure to do something or the other with regards to extracurriculars, and cold hard  disapproval and guilt for not doing anything “productive” during free time.</span></p>
<p class="p4"><span class="s5"> </span><span class="s3">It is also interesting to note that &#8220;free time&#8221; after school and over holidays for many students, in cases where their parents are working,  still means staying at the school . Not only is before and after school care entirely free, but it is not used as an extension of the school day &#8212; there is no school work done at all.  Because of this shift in purpose, it is apparently not regarded by students as an extension of the school day. According to Klara, who regularly participated both before and after school hours and over holidays, it&#8217;s just an opportunity to play with your friends for the day&#8230;. </span><span class="s1">To the other students in our discussion (from India, Canada, the US, and Singapore), the idea of students willingly and gladly spending all outside of school hours and holidays at the same place with the same people as they had attended for school, and being able to distinguish (and happily label!) it as “free-time”,  was certainly remarkably foreign (to say the least).</span></p>
<p class="p4"><span class="s1">On a separate, though possibly related, note involving concepts with the prefix “free-”, it was also observed that the concept of freedom is more clearly framed, and is seen as the liberty to utilize education and access healthcare in order for people to be able contribute their best individually to the collective progress of the community and the country as  a whole. This differs from the notion of freedom in other parts of the world  which is more familiarly correlated with the freedom</span><span class="s6"> “from the government” or the  freedom “to do as you please” (short of criminal acts)  with little regard to who or what it serves or hinders .</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1"> Another, striking difference is the fact that countries across the world, including </span><span class="s2">but not limited to the US</span><span class="s1">, often have an </span><span class="s3">unwritten hierarchy of universities </span><span class="s1">that are deemed to be “elite” and promising with regards to job opportunities after graduation. Such assignation pressurizes students into thinking that getting into these so-designated institutions will be critical for their professional careers, and that not meeting the rigorous demands of these institutions, </span><span class="s7">and by natural extension, those that define &#8220;success&#8221; in society,</span><span class="s1"> will make them redundant to future opportunities.  This kind of  institutional hierarchy does not exist in Sweden. All universities are held on the same pedestal. This might seem easy to dismiss as a simply a fortuitous natural outgrowth of a country that is smaller or more ethnically and ideologically similar, but this seemingly inconsequential ability to imbue institutions and career paths with merit more evenhandedly, seems to produce a meaningful consequence.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The fact that educational autonomy is a likely driving force of happiness on some scale is probably a surprise to no one. The question that is often raised before assigning too much praise, though is  &#8220;what economic &#8216;sacrifices and hardships&#8217; would populations have to &#8216;endure&#8217; from an education system that fuels an economy driven by &#8216;collective prosperity&#8217; and could the companies produced within it compete in an open, and more aggressively competitive global market?&#8221; When people think of socialist economies like Sweden’s, they often assume the high taxation and reduced privatization suffocates entrepreneurism. Yet, evidence from successful companies like Ikea and Spotify, both start-ups created in Sweden, shows that systems like these can facilitate the growth for private companies to function, compete, and succeed in more open market economies. The USA has seen its share of annual new start ups plummet in recent years, while Sweden continues to see record highs (Samuels, A. 2017). America might still be the free capitalists dream, but clear evidence shows that other systems can produce competitive companies, innovative products, and supercharged profits &#8211;ones that thrive not just “not-at-the-expense” of collective prosperity, but rather, because of it. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Many people think of business as a zero-sum game and that while cooperation is useful, too much of it means you’re just allowing your competitors to control your profits. Maximizing autonomy and control in a capitalist system is not simply prized, but is the minimal requirement for business survival. Students in Nordic education systems, however, live in a structure that promotes and values both autonomy and cooperation; in addition,  having grown up with little concern around losing access to education or healthcare, students and future business leaders  are less adverse to more cooperative practices. Certainly this took time. The education system and economic policies in Nordic countries like Sweden were not til fairly recently where they are now.  Initiatives like this in one the 1990s, where<i> “the government gave a tax break to companies that gave their employees home computers, on the condition that these computers were available to everyone, whether they managed the company or cleaned the toilets”</i>….so essentially., “<i>Every inhabitant of Sweden under 40 basically grew up with a PC in their home.”</i> (Samuels, A. 2017).</span><span class="s1">&#8230;were part of the large reforms of the time that started the levelling of the economic playing field and opened the country to the growth and development we now cite. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">In the end, it’s policies that truly level the playing field &#8212; seeing genuine value in cooperation and the real benefit to everyone in granting equal access to resources&#8211;  that may hold the key to collective economic prosperity and general satisfaction (so possibly happiness?). Nordic countries continue to push the point that rather than being first, it’s more productive to work together to come up with the right solution and it looks to be a staple ingredient to many Swedish companies achieving worldwide global success…<br />
Something to take a  hard look at… before thinking that distributing computers to your whole population will solve all your problems.</span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s1">Ollila, J. (April 7, 2019). <i>Op-Ed: Why Finland comes out on top on happiness and more. </i>Los </span><span class="s5">Angeles Times. <a href="https://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-ollila-finland-happiness-20190407-story.html"><span class="s8">https://www.latimes.com/opinion/op-ed/la-oe-ollila-finland-happiness-20190407-story.html</span></a></span></p>
<p class="p5"><span class="s1">Samuels, A. (September 28, 2017). <i>Why Does Sweden Have So Many Start-Ups? </i>The Atlantic. </span><span class="s9"><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2017/09/sweden-startups/541413/"> https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2017/09/sweden-startups/541413/</a></span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Raj, R. (July 8, 2016). <i>Sweden pays students to attend secondary school. </i>inshorts. </span><span class="s9"><a href="https://inshorts.com/en/news/sweden-pays-students-to-attend-secondary-school-1467965">https://inshorts.com/en/news/sweden-pays-students-to-attend-secondary-school-1467965</a></span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1"> </span><span class="s1">Johnston, O., &amp; Wildy, H. (2016). <i>The effects of streaming in the secondary school on learning </i></span><span class="s1"><i>outcomes for Australian students – A review of the international literature.</i> Australian Journal of Education, 60(1), 42–59. https://doi.org/10.1177/0004944115626522</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Mijs, Jonathan. (December 1, 2014). The Unfulfillable Promise of Meritocracy: Three Lessons </span><span class="s1">and Their Implications for Justice in Education Social Justice Research. <i>SSRN. </i>29(1):: </span><span class="s1">https://ssrn.com/abstract=2670274</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/what-is-the-secret-to-happiness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Humanity and Change: 2 Constants in the Face of New Technologies and Green Policies</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/humanity-and-change-in-the-face-of-new-technologies-and-green-policies/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/humanity-and-change-in-the-face-of-new-technologies-and-green-policies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 22:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Academics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.building-u.com/?p=3077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have all heard the phrase “Change is the only constant,” however, the idea of “embracing change” has not quite been embraced. Now more than ever, change is arriving at a rapid pace in terms of advancing technology and environmental policies. As these things start to affect our daily lives, people will be more or [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have all heard the phrase “Change is the only constant,” however, the idea of “embracing change” has not quite been embraced. Now more than ever, change is arriving at a rapid pace in terms of advancing technology and environmental policies. As these things start to affect our daily lives, people will be more or less receptive to the change that is coming. What impacts resistance or receptiveness to change among a population and how does that affect the way technologies such as AI (Artificial Intelligence) and ML (Machine Learning) and policies such as the Green New Deal will be integrated into the world?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main issue that many people bring up regarding AI is job automation and how workers who lose their job are supposed to continue to earn their livelihood. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/amitchowdhry/2018/09/18/artificial-intelligence-to-create-58-million-new-jobs-by-2022-says-report/?sh=bf7b3c64d4ba" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to Forbes</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, though, the continued development of AI is expected to create upwards of 58 million new jobs by 2022. The problem, then, would seem to be the mindset, influenced by any number of factors, that can cause people to automatically and quite possibly incorrectly assume that AI and ML technologies and/or green policies will take away their job. Far from taking away jobs, AI may very well drive people to further enrich the skills that machines cannot replicate. So, despite the fact that AI will displace many workers, AI will also position them to reinvent themselves and their career in a way that pushes them beyond the mundane job tasks that AI would have taken over. In fact, the retraining and reteaching that will be required can allow many to get new, higher paying jobs, ones that can create a renewed <a href="http://ted.com/talks/kai_fu_lee_how_ai_can_save_our_humanity?language=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sense of purpose</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Living with the pandemic has probably made everyone a little clearer on just how important a sense of purpose is. AI is a tool that can bring that sense back into many people’s lives, though it may not look like it on the surface. Jobs that require human compassion, creativity and thought will always be held by humans. Furthermore, the range of human activities that are considered as jobs can be widened. For example: taking care of children, neighbours looking after one another, citizens organizing communities etc. can now expand and be more evenly compensated; in this way there won&#8217;t be any shortage of work even if AI takes over the &#8220;skilled&#8221; workforce.  AI will simply augment these particularly human jobs by analyzing necessary data to optimize the ability to organize and help people to perform them. It&#8217;s also worth noting that professionals such as Ethicists and Philosophers are likely to be in more demand due to the growing need to address AI Ethics in pretty much everything, in addition to controversy surrounding plans to implement or forgo environmental practices and policies. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Green New Deal is an economic policy proposed by the US Green Party suggesting it is false to assume there has to be a choice between climate change energy initiatives and keeping jobs.  According to <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/would-a-green-new-deal-add-or-kill-jobs1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">independent analysis by researchers at The Scientific American</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it is possible to rapidly lower CO2 emissions while also expanding employment over the next three decades. At the heart of the Green New Deal is the idea of pairing a carbon tax and taxes on fossil fuels with  tax incentives for the development and use of cleaner technologies in order to drive economic growth and new industries. Although the concept seems simple enough, there needs to be a credible model(s) for forecasting the impact of this pairing&#8211; a carbon tax and incentivized green energy initiatives&#8211; on jobs specifically. Fortunately there is such a model &#8212; one created by the U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA), as well as versions of it that have been used by prominent research universities&#8211; to actually do just this. This article details the results of varying carbon tax/energy rebate/ job impact models (No tax, moderate tax, and more aggressive tax) and provides a very thorough picture of the particular gains and losses in terms of jobs and $ (energy dividends to households) both in specific regions and across specific industries. The upshot of their analysis is that a moderate carbon tax is actually a win/ win for both secure jobs and a clean environment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the introduction of AI into all kinds of industry and health sectors combined with the changes that climate change and green policies will demand, there is clear controversy not only  around what these changes mean for jobs (more or fewer?) , but also around how people will respond to this need for change. Even with quite a lot of evidence to suggest that there actually might be more jobs, and even with a job market with expanding and &#8220;better&#8221; opportunities&#8221;,  &#8212; individual and community mindsets ultimately influence the receptiveness or resistance to this change and impact how successful this transition will be.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Governments and economic systems play a significant role in creating those mindsets and in people’s receptiveness or resistance which will ultimately influence this transition. There are two main schools of thought that people employ when it comes to embracing change: an individualistic mindset and a collective one. Communities that foster an individualistic mindset that focuses on the individual and their ideas will nurture innovation and creativity. However, they are also the communities that will experience the most resistance to change and will encounter more problems in trying to incorporate new technologies or policies into daily life. People will feel that it is their right to oppose any policies that aren’t favorable to them. They are not thinking about the benefit that it could provide to those around them and the nation itself. In addition to that, if those policies alter generational patterns of certain jobs, such as a family with generations in coal-mining, it can cause additional resistance. Communities that foster a collective mindset with people who think of the greater good rather than what a certain policy does to them individually will encounter less resistance. They focus less on their own ideas and  more on the cumulative population’s ideas and their impact. The priorities that guide the formation of countries and governments differ, so it is not surprising that the manner of optimizing effective change for people in different places will also have to reflect an understanding of the difference in mindsets. In order to make change, each community will require a different incentive to change and policy makers and implementers will have to keep this in mind. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In places where government policies mandating change might be less effective, corporate managers will likely play a large role in the manner and the success of any required transition. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In today&#8217;s globalized society, flexibility and mobility have become essential skills for companies to remain competitive in a rapidly changing landscape. Simply, they are accustomed to change. Given this, corporations are equipped, and will need, to proactively come up with strategies to appease employee resentment from “arbitrary changes” that pose a perceived threat to job security. Maintaining thoughtful communication from the top of management down and keeping employees informed and engaged with the company and industry as a whole can certainly help people feel a <a href="https://hbr.org/1996/05/why-do-employees-resist-change" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">stronger sense of connection</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with their job and can make transitioning much easier. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furthermore, opening up communication channels within larger corporations between <a href="https://hbr.org/1969/01/how-to-deal-with-resistance-to-change" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">middle management</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and their respective teams further boosts the notion that individuals, and their input and welfare, are valued by the company, and in doing so, leads to reduced resistance to change. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultimately, new technologies and new environmental policies will mandate change. Change has been and will always be a sensitive issue to navigate, especially when it involves </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">eliminating long-standing generational jobs and skills.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Afterall, it is human and natural to seek stability and consistency. It may be also interesting and heartening to note, though, that to be successful and effective, any changes in the workforce that will accommodate new technologies and green policies, (whether managed through government policies or corporate initiatives) will require sensitivity and empathy &#8212;  two essential and uniquely human skills that AI will never usurp.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Citations</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brown, Marilyn A. “Would a Green New Deal Add or Kill Jobs?” Ahmadi, Majid. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scientific </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">American. </span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/would-a-green-new-deal-add-or-kill-jobs1/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/would-a-green-new-deal-add-or-kill-jobs1/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Accessed January 2021. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chowdry, Amit. “Artificial Intelligence To Create 58 Million New Jobs By 2022, Says Report” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forbes, </span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/amitchowdhry/2018/09/18/artificial-intelligence-to-create-58-million-new-jobs-by-2022-says-report/?sh=bf7b3c64d4ba"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.forbes.com/sites/amitchowdhry/2018/09/18/artificial-intelligence-to-create-58-million-new-jobs-by-2022-says-report/?sh=bf7b3c64d4ba</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Accessed January 2021</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Harari, Yuval Noah. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Technological Challenge. In 21 Lessons For 21st Century x-18. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">E-book, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jonathan Cape London.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 2018 </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">retrieved from </span><a href="https://media.public.gr/Books-PDF/9781787330870.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://media.public.gr/Books-PDF/9781787330870.pdf</span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“How AI Can save our humanity”, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ted Talk, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">by Kai-Fu Lee. April 2018. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/kai_fu_lee_how_ai_can_save_our_humanity#t-1388"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.ted.com/talks/kai_fu_lee_how_ai_can_save_our_humanity#t-1388</span></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to lower resistance to change when re-designing the work environment. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Service Futures. </span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://www.servicefutures.com/lower-resistance-to-change-when-re-designing-the-work-environment"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.servicefutures.com/lower-resistance-to-change-when-re-designing-the-work-environment</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Accessed January 2021. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jenkins, Aric. “Environmental policy is labor policy, and Biden must make that clear” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fortune. </span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://fortune.com/2020/12/10/biden-climate-policy-coal-mining-jobs-labor/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://fortune.com/2020/12/10/biden-climate-policy-coal-mining-jobs-labor/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Accessed </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">January 2021. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leetaru, Kalev. “What Does It Mean For Social Media Platforms To &#8220;Sell&#8221; Our Data?”. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forbes. </span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kalevleetaru/2018/12/15/what-does-it-mean-for-social-media-platforms-to-sell-our-data/?sh=91189802d6c4"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.forbes.com/sites/kalevleetaru/2018/12/15/what-does-it-mean-for-social-media-platforms-to-sell-our-data/?sh=91189802d6c4</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Accessed January 2021. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leetaru, Kalev. “AI &amp; Big Data’s Hoarding Mentality Creates A New Era Of Cyber Risks” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forbes. </span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kalevleetaru/2019/08/29/ai--big-datas-hoarding-mentality-creates-a-new-era-of-cyber-risks/?sh=6d8be20f3cef"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.forbes.com/sites/kalevleetaru/2019/08/29/ai&#8211;big-datas-hoarding-mentality-creates-a-new-era-of-cyber-risks/?sh=6d8be20f3cef</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Accessed January 2021.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lawrence, Paul. “How to Deal With Resistance to Change” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Harvard Business Review. </span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://hbr.org/1969/01/how-to-deal-with-resistance-to-change"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://hbr.org/1969/01/how-to-deal-with-resistance-to-change</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Accessed January 2021.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mehta, Puneet. “The Alleged Threat Of AI Taking Away Human Jobs Is Not What We Think It </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is.” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forbes,</span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2019/01/17/the-alleged-threat-of-ai-taking-away-human-jobs-is-not-what-we-think-it-is/?sh=1fb9fd7384ed"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbestechcouncil/2019/01/17/the-alleged-threat-of-ai-taking-away-human-jobs-is-not-what-we-think-it-is/?sh=1fb9fd7384ed</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Accessed January 2021.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strebel, P. “Why Do Employees Resist Change?” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Harvard Business Journal. </span></i></p>
<p><a href="https://hbr.org/1996/05/why-do-employees-resist-change"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://hbr.org/1996/05/why-do-employees-resist-change</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Accessed January 2021. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/humanity-and-change-in-the-face-of-new-technologies-and-green-policies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Optional SAT Test Might Not Be So Optional to Students</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/optional-sat-not-so-optional/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/optional-sat-not-so-optional/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 15:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Academics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.building-u.com/?p=2991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With students already having a lot on their plate with college applications, not to mention the stress that comes along with it, covid-19 has further added to the burden on students’ shoulders. With testing centers rapidly cancelling tests during these unprecedented times, most universities were forced to amend their college requirements by either going test-optional, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">With students already having a lot on their plate with college applications, not to mention the stress that comes along with it, covid-19 has further added to the burden on students’ shoulders. With testing centers rapidly cancelling tests during these unprecedented times, most universities were forced to amend their college requirements by either going test-optional, test-blind, test-flexible or dropping the testing requirement altogether. Whilst these changes were made for the convenience of students, the Atlantic reports that, students continued to sign up for these tests, sometimes going an extra mile (quite literally) to drive to neighboring cities or even flying to other states. This raises a critical question about the importance of the SAT/ACT during admissions. It is important to note that the global pandemic has not initiated this debate but has merely catalyzed it. It is also critical to look at the topic of discussion not only with regards to the admissions process, but also from students’ perspectives. After all, they are one of the major, if not the only, stakeholders in this case.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">There have been multiple articles about the future of the SAT/ACT, but finding one about what students think about the amended college requirements is not as easy. In order to address the dearth of students’ voices, we at building-U have conducted a survey of 25 anonymous students, domestic as well as international, addressing multiple aspects of the test taking process, including: one’s likelihood of taking the test, preferability of universities going test-optional/ discontinuing them altogether, students’ point of view on how their test scores affect their future, test preparation process and their final score. Unsurprisingly, 92% of the respondents were either planning to or had already taken the SAT/ACT, with most of them suggesting that the tests were likely to increase their chances of getting into their desired college. The surety of these responses is rather muddled considering the fact that:</span></p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">College admissions often officers reiterate the relatively small  importance of standardized testing</span></li>
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">There is continually increasing consensus for either the test becoming optional or being discontinued altogether</span></li>
</ol>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The assessment of the survey also suggests that 68% students prefer to have universities going test optional with the most dominant reasons being</span></p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li2"><span class="s3"> “Standardized” tests are not a reflection of one’s merit or intelligence</span></li>
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">   Disadvantageous to a certain demographic of people.</span></li>
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">   Lack of accessibility during corona</span></li>
</ol>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Despite the above data, it can be inferred that the reason students continue to sign up for SAT/ACT is because these tests act as a validating measure of their academic success in high school, and its absence will leave students with nothing to hang on to for affirmation. An article published by the </span><span class="s4"><i>New York Times</i></span><span class="s1"> refers to standardized testing as “more democratic and accessible than many of the other metrics used to evaluate applicants,” although in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic, approximately 60 percent of colleges have opted to go test-optional for the fall 2021 admissions cycle. However, some other prominent universities such as the UCs intend to drop the SAT/ACT requirement and develop their own tests,“We are removing the ACT/SAT requirement for California students and developing a new test that more closely aligns with what we expect incoming students to know to demonstrate their preparedness for UC,” says UC President Janet Napolitano. While an approach to making a more &#8220;equitable” test that emphasizes testing students’ “broad based values” may be a good move, it only exemplifies the previously-mentioned quote from </span><span class="s4"><i>the New York Times</i></span><span class="s1">, and reaffirms that some form of &#8220;standardized&#8221; testing, if not the SATs or ACTs, is here to stay. There are two major points that need to be taken into account:</span></p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">If every university starts developing their own tests that puts focus on testing the students for values the university stands for, needless to say, we are essentially retrograding to an even worse scenario especially in terms of students’ mental health and academic course load.</span></li>
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">Even though universities this year have been reassuring students that not reporting their test scores won’t put them at a disadvantage, one must check which universities were test- optional before the pandemic struck and had already independently determined their position on testing, and which universities had no choice but to modify their testing requirement this year, since these two cases are fundamentally different. </span></li>
</ol>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">  Going test-optional is preferable for both students who want to as well as those who don’t want to take any standardized testing. “Standardized tests don’t really accurately determine the type of student one is, but also a high score may be indicative of hard work and determination, so I think test optional is best,” says one respondent; a notion which is explicitly shared by many other students who preferred the tests be made optional.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">It goes without saying that the prospect of standardized testing is very stressful for students. When asked about how much their thoughts and future plans are tied up with </span><span class="s4"><i>thinking</i></span><span class="s1"> about taking the SAT/ACT, on a scale of 1 to 10 (1 being just ‘a passing thought’ and 10 being ‘it consumes my life’) 78% respondents fell into the bracket of 5-10. When further asked about how much their thoughts and future plans are tied to how much they </span><span class="s4"><i>score</i></span><span class="s1"> on the SAT/ACT, on the same scale, 68% fell into the range of 5-10 with a worrying number of 32% selecting a perfect 10.The irony lies in the fact that when asked about how much of their time and thoughts are tied to </span><span class="s4"><i>preparing</i></span><span class="s1"> for the SAT/ACT 32% respondents selected a 5. This data is not in sync with students’ responses on the tests’ anticipated impact on their future.This begs two crucial questions: “Why do students place less significance on preparing for, and spending time on, something that they indicate more significantly impacts their future?”, and “Why do students feel that so much of their academic worth and future ‘success’ is tied up in this test?” Interestingly, many responses were equivocal; students were aware that standardized scores weren’t a mark of intelligence or predictive of their future success, but couldn’t help but feel anxious about them. “This test basically feels like it defines my life, I feel like the SAT is determining how worthy I am, although I know it’s somewhat not true, it consumes up a lot of my thoughts and gives me a lot of anxiety because I feel like this is determining my acceptance into the life I want. I’m also pressured by my parents to do very well and I don’t want to disappoint them, it’s a while away but I stress about it everyday,” says one respondent. Another student also mentions going as far as practicing the test with a mask on, and how that negatively affected their score: “wearing a mask while taking the SAT is extremely difficult. When I took a practice SAT with a mask on at home, my score went down 200 points from its normal range. My glasses fog up with masks, so I had to wear contacts, and you constantly have to blink with contacts on, so you can’t stare at the questions very long without blinking. Also can’t drink water, or take deep breaths to calm down, either. So overall, taking the SAT during the pandemic is a whole other level of difficulty on an already super difficult test,” quotes the student. Needless to say, anxiety and stress of this kind can be detrimental to one’s emotional and mental well being. Nonetheless, it is important to take into consideration, that there are students who feel test scores provide an added piece of information to their application, and may even boost their chances of getting admitted to their university of choice. This is not possible if test requirements are dropped altogether.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">            In the end,  opinions of students who prefer universities going test optional appear to both outweigh and unite the disparity in the extremely polarized opinions of students who either want mandatory testing or want the tests to discontinue altogether,a result that may not be so surprising or unexpected. All-in-all the most significant takeaway from the above research is the small but very clear fact that students seem to hang their personal worth, academic merit, and prospect for future success on a testing system that is at best tenuous and at worst meaningless &#8212; something that warrants both concern and more  discussion with students, not just universities and test makers.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Works Cited</span></p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">Wertheimer, Linda K. “Colleges Are Making the SAT and ACT Optional Now. Will That Stick?” </span><span class="s5"><i>The Boston Globe</i></span><span class="s3">, 1 May 2020, <a href="http://www.bostonglobe.com/2020/05/01/opinion/colleges-are-making-sat-act-optional-now-will-that-stick/"><span class="s1"><b>www.bostonglobe.com/2020/05/01/opinion/colleges-are-making-sat-act-optional-now-will-that-stick/</b></span></a>.</span></li>
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">Currid-halkett, Elizabeth. &#8220;A Pandemic Isn&#8217;t a Reason to Abolish the SAT.&#8221; The New York Times. May 01, 2020. Accessed November 26, 2020. <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/01/opinion/coronavirus-test-optional-sat.html"><span class="s1"><b>https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/01/opinion/coronavirus-test-optional-sat.html</b></span></a>.</span></li>
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">Selingo, Jeffrey. &#8220;The SAT and the ACT Will Probably Survive the Pandemic-Thanks to Students.&#8221; The Atlantic. September 16, 2020. Accessed November 26, 2020. <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/09/even-coronavirus-cant-kill-sat-and-act/616360/"><span class="s1"><b>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/09/even-coronavirus-cant-kill-sat-and-act/616360/</b></span></a>.</span></li>
<li class="li2"><span class="s3">President, UC Office of the. &#8220;University of California Board of Regents Unanimously Approved Changes to Standardized Testing Requirement for Undergraduates.&#8221; University of California. November 24, 2020. Accessed November 26, 2020. https://www.universityofcalifornia.edu/press-room/university-california-board-regents-approves-changes-standardized-testing-requirement#:~:text=However%2C%20if%20a%20new%20test,said%20UC%20President%20Janet%20Napolitano.</span></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/optional-sat-not-so-optional/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Exploring Your Interests</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/the-importance-of-exploring-your-interests/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/the-importance-of-exploring-your-interests/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tamara]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 18:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Academics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.building-u.com/?p=2993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Planning your future is not easy. It takes years of discovering your skills and what you enjoy. Some interests are discovered at a very young age, from when you put on that superhero costume for Halloween, or when you assemble a drone Christmas morning, eager to play with it. What does this teach you about [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Planning your future is not easy. It takes years of discovering your skills and what you enjoy. Some interests are discovered at a very young age, from when you put on that superhero costume for Halloween, or when you assemble a drone Christmas morning, eager to play with it. What does this teach you about yourself? Maybe you’re a leader, the hard-working driven type. Your Wonderwoman costume choice realistically could mean you’re suited for a life in management or politics, a place where you could make a difference. Perhaps building a drone at age 6 means you’re innovative, your creativity skills running wild. You could be constantly stirring up ideas that can one day be a million-dollar investment. It’s often said that high school is where you find that “self-awareness,” yet, self-discovery is a long and ongoing process. Life is not a simple straight path and there is always room for change and growth. No matter what age, your experiences provide the basis for each next decision &#8211; what excites you for tomorrow. According to an article written by Suzanne Johnston, she says “[t]here’s a lot of pressure on high school students to figure what they want ‘to be.’” Her advice is to “[e]xplore. Don’t limit yourself to one area. Take all the classes. Follow your interests.” High school is an amazing opportunity to take risks and get involved, even if you decide it’s not something you want to pursue. The idea that students are expected to maintain an interest all throughout their life is undeniably unreasonable. You are expected to grow out of hobbies; to decide, maybe you want to give up soccer after six years of training. The hope is that by learning through these experiences, you are left with a better understanding of yourself and can adapt and influence any change to come in life; your future is yours to choose. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Post-secondary decisions can be overwhelming. You may have no idea about who or what you want to be. The process of finding what you like or dislike can be dragging and aggravating without the right resources. Every student has unique skills waiting to be unleashed, and new experiences are a gateway to these discoveries. High school can be the perfect time to learn more about yourself and to equip yourself for the future, no matter what you decide to do, and no matter how the path changes. Taking into consideration that there are several specialized courses, clubs, and programs, high school can be more than just the diploma. Once a student is willing to explore outside of their comfort zone, experience failure or discomfort, they become more equipped to take on whatever the future holds. Ian Wilson stated in an article by Suzanne Johnston, “If I were speaking with my Grade 9 self today, I would say find something you are marginally interested in, prepare yourself as best as possible, and buckle up and enjoy the ride! Put your effort into enjoying being in Grade 9… develop friendships, take chances and have fun.” Your freshman and sophomore years are more general and provide you with many opportunities to explore. There is so much to do, learn, and get involved in. For example, challenging yourself to take that advanced placement class can teach you that you like or dislike a fast-paced working environment. It can show that you work better when you are occupied, or when you are working individually. Similarly, working at the nearby food drive teaches you about teamwork and collaboration with your peers. Perhaps you prefer working with others and having a safe, welcoming work environment. All these experiences give you a little more insight into your preferred future. You may learn that you like coding, however, are you willing to work an 8 am shift? Do you like coding for larger companies where you are needed to collaborate or do you prefer working on individual projects? For these reasons and many more, it is important that you rid yourself of boundaries and explore what the world has to offer, as it may surprise you. Although putting yourself out there may seem daunting with the potential to fail, you learn from your failure, and there are many on the road to success. It is valuable to reach out of your comfort zone despite the challenges, as these experiences are what you grow and learn from. Each little internal discovery is another resource at your disposal to inform your own life. Lesley McGilp says, “[w]hen you’re young, you have less to lose and the cost of failure is lower (no car payments, dependents, etc.). It’s a great time to experiment and try new things. You have your whole adult life ahead to apply what you’ve learned. Whether it’s organizing a fundraiser or turning your science fair idea into a business, these are great experiences that build your confidence and skills, even if the first attempt isn’t a success.” Simple activities such as helping your parents put together your new bed or participating in a karaoke event with your friends, help you explore interests. Even though it may not be as evident, these daily experiences help you realize your areas of comfort or discomfort, and show you what an ideal, happy future looks like for yourself.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The Education Department&#8217;s National Center for Education Statistics provided a brief report, stating “almost a third of first-time college students choose a major and then change it at least once within three years.” The author Doug Lenderman continues, “Pearson said he was inclined to attribute the large proportion of students leaving math for other fields more to the reality that college students &#8220;are exposed to new areas of study, like engineering, that don’t have nearly as much visibility in high school&#8221; than to a decision against math.” As much as high school courses may prepare you for post-secondary studies, they can be limiting in terms of experiences and reality. Life can be surprising, and change is often freeing if you are well equipped. Surround yourself in different environments and see how you respond &#8211; learn about yourself. Internships, part-time jobs, and summer co-op programs are all ways to explore interests and grow not only for post-secondary studies but for life. Building-U is a company that helps high school students consider possibilities around areas of interest by providing them with several resources of opportunities all around North America. It’s a platform centred around the development of young-adults, focused on providing ways for them to become aware of more options, recognize their own interests and skills, and embrace the full extent of their capabilities.</span></p>
<p class="p2"><span class="s2">Resources</span></p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li3"><span class="s2">Johnston, Suzanne. “Things We Wish We Knew about Careers and Work When We Were in Grade 9.” </span><span class="s4"><i>Saskatchewan Research Council</i></span><span class="s2">, 1 Nov. 2017, <a href="http://www.src.sk.ca/blog/things-we-wish-we-knew-about-careers-and-work-when-we-were-grade-9"><span class="s5"><b>www.src.sk.ca/blog/things-we-wish-we-knew-about-careers-and-work-when-we-were-grade-9</b></span></a>.</span></li>
<li class="li4"><span class="s1">Lenderman, Doug. </span><span class="s6"><i>Nearly a Third of Students Change Major within Three Years &#8212; Math Majors the Most</i></span><span class="s1">, 8 Dec. 2017, <a href="http://www.insidehighered.com/news/2017/12/08/nearly-third-students-change-major-within-three-years-math-majors-most"><span class="s5"><b>www.insidehighered.com/news/2017/12/08/nearly-third-students-change-major-within-three-years-math-majors-most</b></span></a>.</span></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/the-importance-of-exploring-your-interests/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Empowering Choice</title>
		<link>https://www.building-u.com/empowering-choice/</link>
					<comments>https://www.building-u.com/empowering-choice/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 12:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Academics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.building-u.com/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Imagine yourself, for a moment, going on a picnic in a new country. Packed with all your supplies, you set out to meet your guide. You find them waiting at a crossroads. Behind them are countless sprawling paths, each stretching out to meet the lush nature beyond. From where you stand their destinations are obscured [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Imagine yourself, for a moment, going on a picnic in a new country. Packed with all your supplies, you set out to meet your guide. You find them waiting at a crossroads. Behind them are countless sprawling paths, each stretching out to meet the lush nature beyond. From where you stand their destinations are obscured yet each is ripe with promise; you look to your guide for help. You tell her what you are looking for: a nice quiet place with a beautiful view. She assures you she knows the perfect spot, and, with a smile, is off down one of the paths, beckoning you to follow. You hike on the worn dirt until sunlight gives way to shade and the path grows narrow and winding, stretching upward through windswept pines. Soon you reach a clearing on a peak where the trees break to frame a verdant forest painting a tall, spanning valley. The guide leaves you to your picnic. The view is spectacular and it is quiet enough, but as you rest your feet and unpack your bag, the wind begins to chill, the ground hard beneath. You can’t help but wonder where the other paths might have taken you. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Now, imagine you are back at that same crossroads, describing again your hopes for your picnic. But this time, instead of taking the lead herself, she begins to describe each path, what she knows, and what awaits at each end. Armed with information, you set off. The first path you head down leads you to a mossy clearing nestled deep in the woods. The air is still and meditative, the only sound the rustling of leaves, but with naught a view but the endless oaks, you head back from where you came, in search of a better path. The next trail you embark on leads to a waterfall, whose crystal water splashes on the rocks to mix with the sun in a hazy shifting rainbow. The sight beautiful but the noise deafening, you head back once again. However, your next path leads you to a meadow. The clearing stretches wide before you, soft grass peppered with wildflowers nestled between a great forest, only dwarfed by the mountains rising to meet the sun. Finally, you sit, and have your perfect picnic. Making the right choice is not always easy and will take consideration and can take time. However, with patience and knowledge, one can use the resources at their disposal to forge their own path, and find the place that is right for them. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Life is a stream of decisions, small and large. Whether deciding what to eat at a restaurant or planning the next big step in life, choice is unavoidable, and this is especially true for high school students. As the next phase of their lives looms, post secondary planning can be a difficult, overwhelming process and it is common for students to feel indecisive about their next step and look for guidance. According to a study published in the Journal of Counselling Psychology by Germeijs, Verschueren, and Soenens, this “indecisiveness [does] not turn out to be a risk factor for students’ awareness of the need to make a decision and motivation to engage in the career decision process” (407). Students remain undeterred and will still make a decision in this situation. Furthermore, a study published in the College and University Journal which covers how high school seniors construct decision-making strategies for choosing colleges, found that “students use less complex decision making strategies to select colleges, not because it is better to do so but because it may be simpler and more comfortable” (26). These studies show the difficulty in this decision making process for the students, highlight their motivation and need to engage despite limited personal skills and strategies, and make an unhealthy reliance on input from others understandable. It also gives clearer insight into potentially better ways to help them. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">In order for proper guidance and preparation to make a significant impact on a student’s preparedness for postsecondary decisions, it must strengthen </span><span class="s2">a</span><span class="s1"> student’s decision making ability: a necessary life skill. Guidance must have an emphasis on education and resource provision and a problem based context or component; it involves helping students develop decision-making skills, rather than helping them make decisions. As stated in the paper </span><span class="s3"><i>The Educating of Students&#8217; Decision Making Competence in the Problem Based Learning Context: Facing the Perspective of the Contemporary Knowledge Society, “</i></span><span class="s1">the school and parents task is not to be a decision maker, even with the best knowledge, of what the child or the society needs, but to be the best enabler of student autonomy, providing the competence for making the decision” (www.leeds.ac.uk/educol/documents/00003289.htm). Moreover, according to </span><span class="s3"><i>A Taxonomy of Difficulties in Career Decision Making</i></span><span class="s1"> published in the Journal of Counseling Psychology, the working world is becoming increasingly dynamic with an increase in the number of career transitions people make in their lifetime, so dealing with choice and tackling change are more important skills than ever (510).</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Building-U embraces the idea of informing decision-making skills by empowering choice for young adults. Whatever a student’s postsecondary plans may be, building-U provides the resources for them to not only build a framework for postsecondary decisions, but develop skills that can serve them well for a lifetime.</span></p>
<p class="p4"><span class="s1">Resources</span></p>
<ol class="ol1">
<li class="li5"><span class="s1">Gati, Itamar, et al. “A Taxonomy of Difficulties in Career Decision Making.” </span><span class="s4"><i>Journal of Counseling Psychology</i></span><span class="s1">, vol. 43, no. 4, 1996.</span></li>
<li class="li5"><span class="s1">Germeijs, Veerle, et al. “Indecisiveness and High School Students’ Career Decision-Making Process: Longitudinal Associations and the Mediational Role of Anxiety.” </span><span class="s4"><i>Journal of Counseling Psychology</i></span><span class="s1">, vol. 53, 2006.</span></li>
<li class="li5"><span class="s1">Govan, George V., et al. “How High School Students Construct Decision-Making Strategies for Choosing Colleges.” </span><span class="s4"><i>College and University</i></span><span class="s1">, vol. 81, 2006.</span></li>
<li class="li5"><span class="s1">Siauciukeniene, Liuda; “The Educating of Students&#8217; Decision Making Competence in the Problem Based Learning Context: Facing the Perspective of the Contemporary Knowledge Society.” </span><span class="s4"><i>University of Leeds</i></span><span class="s1">, Education-Line, 27 Oct. 2003, www.leeds.ac.uk/educol/documents/00003289.htm.</span></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.building-u.com/empowering-choice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
